Wayne W. Grigsby

Data Engineer





grigswa@gmail.com



Washington DC



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Over the past eight years, I have successfully adapted to a growing industry by continuing to expand upon my knowledge of cutting-edge technologies. Currently, I am developing enhanced analytic products for the Dept. of Justice on behalf of Deloitte. Prior to my time with Deloitte, I developed coded solutions to analyze DoD data center information providing insights into costs, compliance, and utilization. Before that, I worked with Interpol to develop scripts that enabled Counterterrorism Analysts to more efficiently track and target terrorist travel patterns. No matter what I choose to do, I will continue to bring the high level of enthusiasm, hard work, knowledge and common sense I have come to be known for.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python HTML & CSS Javascript SQL Oracle PostgreSQL SQLite Django

Heroku PyCharm

Tableau

.....

Git

MAC, Windows, LINUX Microsoft SharePoint

EDUCATION

BACHELORS DEGREE Political Science Columbus State University

EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST

Deloitte | Department of Justice | Dec 2017 - Present Washington, DC

As the sole data scientist on a service transition and technology transformation project, it is my responsibility to build an analytics team within our program. To achieve this I have begun adapting existing processes and data reporting methods to modern standards such as Tableau. Additionally, I am in the process of designing an analytical platform to complement existing applications. Other duties include data analysis, databases scripting, data wrangling, modeling, and designing visualizations. In addition to my role on this project, I provide data analytic products to Deloitte, on a case-by-case basis.

- Write SQL /PLSQL scripts to pull and structure data from large Oracle databases
- Analyze and organize unstructured data
- Design analytic platform to work independently from primary application
- Automate existing data analysis reports with Python
- Use Tableau to analyze and visualize structured/unstructured data
- Develop scripts with Python (pandas, numpy, pyplot, etc) to restructure, analyze and visualize insights
- Write white papers to provide researched data analytic solutions to the Government

DATA ENGINEER

Booz Allen Hamilton | Office of the Secretary of Defense | Oct 2017 - Nov 2017 Washington, DC

In my role as a data engineer, one of my primary tasks was to collect and analyze DoD data center audit data. This data had been collected over the past four years and contained the bulk of what the DoD knew about each individual data center. The purpose of this research and analysis was to understand whether data centers were compliant with current rules and regulations.

- Designed and developed local SQLite databases to store data
- Developed a python scripts (with pandas, numpy, pyplot) to gather, sort, identify key insights, and visually present these findings
- Developed detailed associated documentation to accompany the final product, along with my findings
- Provided technology recommendations to the government regarding data analytics

Wayne Grigsby | Technology & Data Analyst





grigswa@gmail.com



Washington DC



SKILLS

Attention to Detail Strong Interpersonal Skills Strong Communication Skills Team Leadership **Project Planning** Agile Methodology **Process Improvement Customer Service** Resource Management Project Management Data Collection Quantitative Analysis Qualitative Analysis Research Creativity Writing

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING

ITIL V3 Certification
Introduction to Python
Django Introduction
ISO 20000:1 Foundations
CompTIA A+ Certification
Administering SharePoint
Windows Server Administration
FSO Management

EXPERIENCE continued

INDEPENDENT TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

Oct 2016 - Sept 2017 Lyon, France

As an independent consultant, I developed scripts for Interpol Counterterrorism Analysts to more efficiently structure and visualize their data. I also provided Interpol officials with recommendations to improve their utilization of existing technology while operating within the constraints of a limited budget. I also continued to assist US organizations with technology procurement decisions, while simultaneously developing a working web app (vvayne.co).

- Analyzed Interpol processes and provided recommendations for improvement
- Repaired and deployed VBA scripts for Interpol General Secretariat (IPSG)
- Trained Interpol employees how to use new scripts and analyze data
- Developed Python scripts to manage financial transactions
- Utilized APIs to pull currency data and provide financial transactions an accurate conversion
- Developed Diango website to house financial tracking app
- Deployed Django apps on Heroku, and manage postgreSQL database
- Utilized bootstrap 3 and developed custom css to design Django website for desktop/mobile

TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

Booz Allen Hamilton | Office of the Secretary of Defense | June 2016 - Oct 2016 Washington, DC

Within the Office of the Secretary Defense, the Business Process Systems Review (BPSR) staff focused on efficiencies and new emerging technologies. As a Technology Analyst for the BPSR office, I focused my efforts on enabling the Department of Defense with data to enable effective decision making. Researching and analyzing costs, potential savings, and returns on investment were integral to providing the Government with viable solutions to their enterprise issues. Our findings were then used to understand the limits of our annual budget in contrast to existing costs, contracts, and the ROI of proposed technology procurements.

- Analyzed software capabilities and costs in parallel with allotted budget to provide leadership with viable solutions
- Served as a liaison between the Government, industry, and contract teams
- Engaged industry in an effort to discuss and deliver solutions to complex enterprise issues
- Collected and analyzed complex data from a multitude of sources
- Delivered data visualizations to leadership enabling effective decision making
- Managed software demos and analyzed data output with a focus on potential process impact
- Reviewed and edited new capability proposals, storyboards, and use cases to consolidate technological realities with expected outcomes
- Collaborated with industry experts to determine ways in which the Government could effectively utilize new emerging technologies
- Coordinated industry outreach efforts in support of DOD technology requirements
- Managed Senior Executive Service (SES) officials and provided task deliverable support to provide maximum efficiency and availability of BPSR leadership

TECHNOLOGY STRATEGIST

Booz Allen Hamilton | Joint Chiefs of Staff | Aug 2014 - June 2016 Washington, DC

As a member of the Information Management Division of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, I managed a multitude of technology, process improvement, and knowledge management projects. My mission was to enhance the use of collaborative tools and applications among Joint Staff members and partners. These efforts enabled the Joint Staff to

Wayne Grigsby | Technology & Data Analyst





grigswa@gmail.com



Washington DC



LANGUAGES

Spanish: Proficient French: Proficient German: Beginner

LINKS

vvayne.co Github Linkedin

EXPERIENCE continued

efficiently communicate and collaborate with Combatant Commands and successfully execute the agenda of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.

- Translated complex technological concepts to the government client in an effort to spread information and knowledge
- Developed strategies for achieving information management, knowledge management, and information technology goals
- Performed analysis of IT programs, business processes, and technology policies
- Solely cleared a 3 year project backlog within 6 months
- Served as a liaison between technology teams, government personnel, and vendors
- Provided recommendations, guidance, and counsel to leadership regarding technology concepts and policy to enhance decision making

SYSTEMS ANALYST

 $\label{eq:MymicLLC} \mbox{MymicLLC} \ | \ \mbox{Joint Chiefs of Staff} \ | \ \mbox{Sept 2013 - Aug 2014} \ \mbox{Washington, DC}$

As an analyst for the Joint Staff IT Department, I worked closely with every office to ensure the usage and understanding of the Joint Staff's collaborative tools remained optimal. I led multiple efforts to enhance web sites and to develop SharePoint applications. I also worked with government clients to analyze existing processes in an effort to determine a more efficient way, utilizing technology, to enhance these processes.

- Provided technology, business process and knowledge management recommendations and support to the Joint Staff and its components
- Designed enterprise solutions that utilized authoritative data sources within the Joint Staff environment
- Served as the sole point of contact for the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff's office in all Technology matters
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JAVASCRIPT to design and develop SharePoint sites

LEAD IT SPECIALIST

Knight Point Systems | Oct 2011 - Sept 2013 Reston, VA

As the sole IT resource in a newly-established IT department, I developed and managed all IT assets, processes, and company certifications for three rapidly growing companies (300+ employees). I significantly upgraded and advanced the technology and performance of the companies' IT systems while working within the constraints of a limited budget. Additionally, I successfully balanced the roles of systems/network administrator, security officer, help desk, and ISO 20000 quality manager.

- Developed methodologies on a situational basis to increase the performance and reliability of the network and system's infrastructure
- Successfully completed and passed 3 annual ISO 20000:1 audits
- Designed and developed a company service catalog to track all IT assets and associated documentation
- Developed and maintained change management, risk management, and content management policies
- Designed and developed a custom ticketing system within SharePoint to track all issues, risks, and changes
- Administered networks, servers, and VOIP services